Guide to the American Federation of Teachers, Local 2097 Records, 1970-1982 AIS.1983.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Federation of Teachers, Local 2097 Records
1970-1982
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Federation of Teachers. Local 2097 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1983.03
3.75 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
The North Allegheny Federation of Teachers chartered in November 1970 and serves as the collective bargaining agent for teachers working in the North Allegheny School District. This collection includes contracts and materials from contract negotiations between NAFT and the district.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the North Allegheny Federation of Teachers in 1983.
History
The North Allegheny Federation of Teachers chartered in November 1970 and serves as the collective bargaining agent for teachers working in the North Allegheny School District. In addition, the union local sponsors scholarships to students in the district.
Previous Citation
American Federation of Teachers, Local 2097 Records, 1970-1982, AIS.1983.03, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes contracts and materials from contract negotiations between the North Allegheny Federation of Teachers and North Allegheny School District, particularly from 1979 and 1981. Also included is information about the organizing of American Federation of Teacher Local 2097 and grievances against the school district.
Related Material
American Federation of Teachers Local 2067, 1966-1981, AIS.1981.15, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
American Federation of Teachers Local 2340 Records, 1971-1983, AIS.1983.23, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Labor; Education; Teachers' unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh Region; North Allegheny School District (Pa.); American Federation of Teachers. Local 2097 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); North Allegheny Federation of Teachers (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Constitution (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Organization, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
- Charter, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Contracts, 1973, 1976, 1978, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
- Paraprofessional Contract, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Negotiations, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, Senior High, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, Intermediate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, Carson, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, Ingomar Middle and Bradford, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, Franklin and Ingomar Elementary, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Negotiations: Faculty Questionaires, McKnight and Hosack, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Negotiations: NAFT Proposal, January 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
- Negotiations, January-September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
- Negotiations,School District Proposal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Negotiations,Questionaire Results, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Negotiations,Salary Comparisons, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Negotiations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Paraprofessional Negotiations, NAFT Proposal, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Negotiations, Questionaires and Contract Language, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28-39)
- Negotiations, Preliminary Questionaires, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 40-56)
- Negotiations, Insurance Questionaires, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 57-65)
- Negotiations, Insurance Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1-16)
- Negotiations, Questionaires, Transfers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17-21)
- Negotiations, Teaching Load Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22-33)
- Negotiations, Salary and Extra Duties Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Negotiations, Intramurals Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 35-38)
- Negotiations, Non-Athletic Supplements Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 39-43)
- Negotiations, Athletics Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 44-49)
- Negotiations, Lincoln Life Surveys, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Negotiations, Commentary Summary Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Negotiations, Summaries Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
- Negotiations, Information Questionaires, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Negotiations, Savings Bond Program, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Negotiations, Supplements Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Negotiations, Cross References, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Negotiations, Working Contract Copy, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Negotiations, Draft Contract Articles, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Negotiations, Supplemental Contracts List, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Negotiations, Salary Step Projections, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Negotiations, Working Contract Copy, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Negotiations, Proposals, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Negotiations, Supplements, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Negotiations, Member's Suggestions, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Negotiations, Legal Background, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Negotiations, Contract Comparisons, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Negotiations, Salary Schedules, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 68-70)
- Negotiations, October 1980-May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 71-72)
- Negotiations, August 1981 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Negotiations,Chronological Work Sheet, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Comparative Salary Information, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 75-76)
- Grievance Issues, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Grievances, 1971-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1-21)
- Ledger, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Checking Account, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
- Finances, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 25-31)
- Per Capita, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
- Comparative and General Collective Bargaining Information (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Scheduling, Assignments and Flextime, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Mini-Grants, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Scovel Leave of Absence, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- New Teachers, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Armstrong Resignation and Betty Schools Survey, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Executive Council Minutes, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- AFT Mailings, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Photographs (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Office Employees Handbook, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Supplemental Contracts, Articles under Negotiation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
- Act of General Assembly, State,Number 195, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Proposed Contract with Teamsters Local 205, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Negotiating Session Minutes, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Arbitrator Selection, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Madden Grievance, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Material on Clericals, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Federation Rights, Articles under Negotiation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Leaves of Absence, Articles under Negotiation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Articles under Negotiation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 57-58)
- NASD Contract Counter Proposal, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Contract Proposal, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Salary Articles under Negotiation and Wage Scales, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 61)